RESUME LINH, NGUYEN HOANG





SUMMARY

10 years of experience managing start-up high-tech (hardware & software) companies.

8 years of experience as Senior Business Development Manager – B2B in MNC.

12 years as Business Director in Information System Solution Provider companies.

Strong IT background by professional training; strong project management, people management, B2B sales and marketing on-job experiences over 25 years.

EXPERIENCE

Otopro Car Audio Garage system - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Business co-founder. Sep. 2019 - Present

- Expand OtoPro Car Audio chain store in the South.
- · Hands-on in everything from setting up stores, recruiting staff, and training to building processes
- Establish relationships with partners and suppliers in the south.
- Operate business and manage sales.

Geek Up - an efficient software development company for big corporates - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Geek Up is a digital product development company that focuses on delivering impactful products through our end-to-end solutions. In 9 years of operations, they have been creating 170+ products that contribute real value for more than 80 local and international companies, making Geek Up a "trusted product partner" for many businesses.

Business Development Director. Full-time in 2022 and Partnership in 2023

Duties:

- Propose and implement business strategies.
- Creating a sales flow and organizing the Sales and Marketing team.
- Develop and maintain relationships with decision-makers in big corporates.
- Present business proposals to C levels customers, and follow up to close deals.
- Provide mentorship to help the tech leaders develop the business mindset to take on more responsibility.

Achievement:

Generated Leads has a growth rate of nearly 70% in the first half of 2023.

Won 4 big corporate client and many medium contracts in 1 year.

NanoTech - a Fintech company - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Nanotech is a start-up business, aiming to provide Salary on-demand Services. We focus to engage B2B customers with the company having more than 5000 employees.

Client Solutions Director. Full time in 2021 and Partnership in 2022

Duties:

- Propose and implement business strategies.
- Propose pricing structure and discount scheme.
- Present business proposals to C levels customers, and follow up to close deals.
- Develop and maintain relationships with strategic partners (HR Outsourcing; HR software; HR talent recruitment...)
- Together with the owner to establish company culture, sales target and fare incentive structures to grow and retain people
- Team coaching to improve sales performance. Provide mentorship to help the team develop the skills required to grow and take on more responsibility

Achievement:

- Won more than 20 corporate clients (Retail, Service, Manufactory...) & 4 strategic partners
- Acquired more than 30,000 app users

Samsung Electronics - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Senior Business Development Manager & Presales Leader. Dec. 2012 – Aug. 2019

Duties:

- Explore potential markets to develop Samsung Display and Mobile solutions. Focus on targeted B2B customers in Health care, Hospitality, Government, Transportation, telecommunication, and retail industry.
- Provide direct solution consultation, and client management in complex projects (Government, Hospitality), and coordinate with the sales team to win and close deals as soon as possible.
- Main responsible to manage partnerships, coach Sales for excellent, lead B2B pre-sales team with 2 people nationwide, organize products & solutions training courses.
- Lead and launch a project to build the biggest B2B Digital Showroom in SEA.

Achievement:

- B2B team achieved grow rate average of 20% 30% yearly in 7 years
- Successfully launch the biggest B2B Digital Showroom in SEA on schedule. This showroom is a strong engagement touchpoint to give B2B customers really experience with Samsung B2B Solutions. (> 550 attendees annually)
- Lead B2B marketing activities to achieve > 18% conversation rate on any activity (Sponsoring and Samsung-owned events).
- Develop new partners (local and international partners) to build integrated solutions, that fulfill clients' demands. (~3 solutions annually)

ITD Location Corporation, members of ITD Group - Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

ITD Location's vision was to become the technology company leading in providing GPS Fleet Tracking & Management Solution Vietnam.

Managing Director. Oct. 2009 - Jul. 2012

Duties:

- Form a Start-up company. Built-up new team: technical R&D, Production, Sales and Marketing team,
 Customer Services Team.
- Develop go-to-market strategy, mass production, Sales, Marketing, and Customer Service, driving business objectives, managing company P&L.
- · Explored and managed the partnership with different suppliers, vendors local and international

Achievement:

- Ahead with the Go-to-market plan schedule, became the 1st Location-Based System (LBS) in Vietnam for Vehicle tracking in 2011. The business has good revenue right in the 1st year;
- Built and maintain strong partnerships with the 3 biggest Telco companies in VN (Mobifone, Viettel, and Vinaphone) together to come up with a Commercial version of GPS Fleet Tracking Solution.
- Successful on-time with recruitment plan for the new company; built company process and called for more funding capital.

HPTLink Technology Corporation – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

HPTLink, a Start-up company of HPT Vietnam Corporation, with the ambition to be the 1st company in Vietnam to develop GPS Tracking Device and lead the GPS Fleet Management Tracking Solution market

Product Director & Managing Director. Jan. 2006 – Jun. 2009

Duties:

- Set up and operate a startup the company for R&D GPS Fleet tracking device and solution (hardware and software) in 03 phases: R&D, Mass production, Go-to-market;
- Recruit, manage people, and expand the company over each growing phase.
- Direct in-charge from market education, partners/ suppliers' management, to customer engagement.
- Built entire Fleet Tracking solution from hardware to software.
- Ensure the company grows in-plan, healthy P&L with investors' expectations
- Prepared detailed financial forecasts and raised funding from private investors

Achievement:

- Successfully launched the 1st GPS Fleet tracking system in Vietnam in 2008, 100% made by Vietnamese people from GPS hardware devices to GPS Fleet tracking software systems.
- Successful delivery of the ambition of BOD as the 1st launching GPS Device in Vietnam.
- Selling 200 devices within 1st month of launching with only 1.3% errors.
- Partnership with 3 telco companies to build and launch Fleet Management Solution with 2 GPS devices version CDMA and GPRS (S-Fone, Mobifone, Viettel, Vinaphone, ...)
- Won deals with logistics & transportation companies in the South, and local Banking in the North.

HPT Vietnam Corporation – Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

HPT is an international-rank ICT company. They would like to become the leading technology company in providing solutions and services of ICT, software development and integrating other advanced technologies.

Managing Director of HPT Customer Service Center. Jan. 2002 – Dec. 2005

Duties:

- Manage after-Sale Services Center (CSC) with > 30 people.
- Manage daily management duties including Human Resource Management, P&L, Operation process, target Sales and services revenue.
- Driving superior customer service, which will support and enhance the overall Customer Experience.
- · Expanding more CSC to HN, Da Nang.

Achievement:

- Achieve more than 100% of target revenue.
- Maintaining increasing revenue of 30% every year from 2003 to 2005
- Generated 40% Margin of Revenue.
- Turn CSC from a non-profit center into a Profit center by developing a new business model that is suitable for CSC to make more sales.
- Successful build-up and apply new Centralization Management System to CSC.
- Build up, maintain, and improve the Customer Care process standard following ISO9002.
- Develop new value-added services every year.

Vice Director of HPT Customer Service Center. Jan. 1999 – Dec. 2001.

Duties:

- Managing After-Sell (Product Support & Maintenance) Services Center, for HP products including HP Server, PC, Laptop, Scanner, Printer, Plotter (Large Format Printer)... etc., more than 30 different models
- · Organize and conduct technical training, soft-skill training for internal staff
- Solving technical and service problems, then building a working process to improve quality of service
- · Created effective and productive with a high level of positive energy working environment.

Achievement:

- Successful development and apply QC ISO9002 1994, which helps to improve the quality and effectiveness of the working process.
- Remain the perfect customer service level at CSC.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE/ PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Sales and Business Development
- Strategy Management
- Team Management
- Negotiation
- Product & Solution Development

- Presentation Skills
- · Leadership in Organizations
- Internal & External Communications
- Interpersonal Skills

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

University of Science – VNUHCM: **Valedictorian of Master** of **Computer Science**, **Faculty of Physics**. 1995 – 1998

University of Science – VNUHCM: **Valedictorian** of **Bachelor of Science**, Electronic Major, **Faculty of Physics**. 1991 – 1995

PACE Institute. Certificate of Accounting for CEO. 2011

PACE Institute. Certificate of Finance for Leaders and Managers Course. 2009

CBAM Institute. Certificate of Strategy Management. 2004

CBAM Institute. Certificate of Leadership in Organizations. 2003

Application Management Center (AMC). Certificate of Expert Assessment of Quality - System management standards ISO 9000. 1997

HP (Hewlett Packard). HP AIS (Accredited Integration Specialist) certification - Q.4 2004

HP. The "Proliant University" certification – 2002

HP. HP Network Storage Solutions Sales certification – 2002

Cisco, CCNA certification - 2001

ADDITIONAL - PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Language: Vietnamese & English
- Business Performance-oriented, Profitability senses
- A Charismatic Leader.
- Exceptional Attention to detail & Well-organized
- Enthusiastic, competent and diligent

- Hunger for success in every part of work.
- Outstanding Team work
- The ability to stay calm under pressure
- · Open-minded